Sign in

Privacy Policy
==============

Last Updated: July 16, 2024

Thank you for using SpanishDictionary.com, inglés.com, and FrenchDictionary.com! Our mission is to bring high quality reference and education products to every Spanish, English, and French learner in the world. To do that, we show you personalized services and ads that we think will be relevant based on the information we collect from you and third parties.

We recognize the importance of protecting your personal information. We wrote this Privacy Policy to describe how we collect, use, and share your information in connection with your use of the SpanishDictionary.com services, including the SpanishDictionary.com website, located at SpanishDictionary.com (the "Website"), mobile applications (the "Application"), or other online services provided under the SpanishDictionary.com name (collectively, the "SpanishDictionary.com Services").

When we mention "SpanishDictionary.com", "inglés.com", "FrenchDictionary.com", "we", "us", "our", or "Curiosity Media", we are referring to the company that owns and operates SpanishDictionary.com, inglés.com, and FrenchDictionary.com, Curiosity Media, Inc.

By using the SpanishDictionary.com Services or submitting any personally identifiable information to us, you consent to our collection, use, and disclosure of information about you as described in this Privacy Policy.

If you have any comments regarding this policy, please let us know by contacting us [here](https://help.spanishdict.com/).

Table of Contents
-----------------

How We Collect Information
--------------------------

In order to offer the SpanishDictionary.com Services, we rely on the ability to collect, store, and analyze basic information about how people interact with our website and other products. We also engage in agreements with third party partners who help us to provide our services, analyze our data, and deliver a customized and high-quality user experience. As such, we and our third party partners may collect and store personal information about you when you use SpanishDictionary.com Services. This information can come from information you provide to us, technical information that is shared with us, and third party information that is shared with us, each of which we describe below.

### Information You Provide to Us

When you use the SpanishDictionary.com Services, you may provide information to us voluntarily. This information includes:

1. **Account Information:** If you create an account, we may store and use your name, username, email address, birthday, gender, and other information you may provide with your account. You can modify some of the information associated with your account [here](https://www.spanishdict.com/users/settings). If you link your Facebook or Google account to the SpanishDictionary.com Services, we also may get information from those accounts, such as your email and contacts. The information we get depends on your settings and their privacy policies. If you use the SpanishDictionary.com Services on your mobile device, including through our Application, we may collect your phone number and the unique device id number. If you tell us where you are (e.g., by allowing your mobile device to send us your location), we may store and use that information to provide you with location-based advertising. If you want to deactivate this feature, you can either reinstall the Application or deactivate GPS on your mobile device.
2. **Content:** The content that you contribute to SpanishDictionary.com Services is intended for public consumption, including your vocabulary lists, forum posts, comments, and other content contributions.
3. **Preferences:** Our Website lets you store preferences like how your content is displayed, your location, safe search settings, etc. We may associate these choices with your ID, browser or mobile device, and you can edit these preferences at any time.
4. **Billing:** When you order a subscription on our Application, we will collect all information necessary to complete the transaction, including your name, credit card information, and billing information.
5. **Communications:** When you sign up for an account or use certain features, you are opting to receive messages from us and other users. You can manage some of your messaging preferences [here](https://www.spanishdict.com/users/settings), but note that you cannot opt out of receiving certain administrative, transactional, or legal messages from us. We may also track your actions in response to the messages you receive from the SpanishDictionary.com Services, such as whether you deleted, opened, or forwarded such messages. If you exchange messages with others through SpanishDictionary.com Services, we may store them in order to process and deliver them, allow you to manage them, and we may review and disclose them in connection with investigations related to the operation and use of SpanishDictionary.com Services. We may also store information that you provide through communications to us, including from phone calls, letters, emails, and other electronic messages.
6. **Surveys:** We may collect and store personal information if you choose to participate in voluntary internet or telephone based surveys that help us learn more about our users. These survey results are generally not shared externally, but if they are, the results must be in an aggregate or anonymized form.
7. **Other:** We may also collect other forms of personally identifiable information, such as at other points on our Website or Application that state personally identifiable information is being collected.

### Information You Provide to Social Networking Sites

The SpanishDictionary.com Services include interfaces that allow you to connect with social networking sites (each, a “SNS”). If you connect to a SNS through the SpanishDictionary.com Services, you authorize us to access, use and store the information that you agreed the SNS could provide to us based on your settings on that SNS. We will access, use and store that information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. You can revoke our access to the information you provide in this way at any time by amending the appropriate settings from within your account settings on the applicable SNS.

### Technical Information that we Collect

When you use the SpanishDictionary.com Services, we collect certain technical information automatically. This information includes:

1. **Log data:** When you use the SpanishDictionary.com Services, our servers record information ("Log data"). This may include your IP address, searches, browser type and settings, the data and time of your request, how you used SpanishDictionary.com, Cookie data, and Device data.
2. **Device data:** In addition to log data, we collect information about the device on which you’re using the SpanishDictionary.com Services, including the type of device, operating system, settings, unique device identifiers and crash data that helps us understand when something breaks. Whether we collect some or all of this information often depends on what type of device you’re using and its settings. For example, different types of information are available depending on whether you’re using a Mac or a PC, or an iPhone or Android phone. To learn more about what information your device makes available to us, please also check the policies of your device manufacturer or software provider.
3. **Cookie data:** We, and third parties with whom we partner, may use cookies, web beacons, scripts, local storage, flash cookies, advertising identifiers (including mobile identifiers such as Apple’s IDFA or Google’s Advertising ID) and similar technologies ("Cookies") in connection with your use of SpanishDictionary.com Services. Cookies may have unique identifiers, and reside, among other places, on your computer or mobile device, in emails we send to you, and on our web pages. Cookies may transmit information about you and your use of SpanishDictionary.com Services. For example, we use Cookies to store your language preferences or other settings so you don‘t have to set them up every time you visit SpanishDictionary.com. Cookies may be persistent or stored only during an individual session. Some of the Cookies we use are associated with your SpanishDictionary.com account (including information about you, such as the email address you gave us) and other Cookies are not. It may be possible to disable some (but not all) Cookies through your device or browser settings, but doing so may affect the functionality of the SpanishDictionary.com Services. The method for disabling Cookies may vary by device and browser, but can usually be found in preferences or security settings. For example, iOS and Android devices each have settings which are designed to limit forms of ad tracking. You can find more information about Cookies and how they work, what Cookies have been set on your computer or mobile device and how to manage and delete them at [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) and [www.youronlinechoices.com/uk](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk). Please note that changing any of these settings does not prevent the display of all advertisements to you. For more information on the types of Cookies we use and their purposes, please review the table below:

| Type | Purpose |
| --- | --- |
| Essential | Intended to make the SpanishDictionary.com Services work in the way you expect. For example, we use a Cookie that tells us whether you have already signed up for an account. |
| Authentication, Security, and Compliance | Intended to prevent fraud, protect your data from unauthorized parties, and comply with legal requirements. For example, we use Cookies to determine if you are logged in. |
| Preferences | Intended to remember information about how you prefer the SpanishDictionary.com Services to behave and look. For example, we use a Cookie that tells us whether you have muted audio in our some of our quizzes. |
| Notifications | Intended to allow or prevent notices of information or options that we think could improve your use of the SpanishDictionary.com Services. For example, we use a Cookie that stops us from showing you a certain signup notification if you have already seen it. |
| Advertising | Intended to make advertising more relevant to users and more valuable to advertisers. For example, we may use Cookies to serve you interest-based ads, such as ads that are displayed to you based on your visits to other websites, or to tell us if you have recently clicked on an ad. |
| Social Media | Intended to allow you to use social media websites while using the SpanishDictionary.com Services. For example, when you sign up for an account using a social media site, the site will use a Cookie to indicate that you have signed in to our site. |
| Analytics | Intended to help us understand how visitors use the SpanishDictionary.com Services. For example, we use a Cookie that tells us how our search suggestions correlate to your interactions with the search page. |

### Third Party Information We Collect

We may also obtain information about you and your activity outside SpanishDictionary.com from our affiliates, advertisers, partners and other third parties we work with, or other publicly available sources. For example, online advertisers or third parties may share information with us to measure or improve the performance of ads on the SpanishDictionary.com Services, or to figure out what kinds of ads to show you. This includes information about your visits to an advertiser's site or purchases you made from them, or information about your interests from a third party service, which we might use to help show you ads.

How We Use the Information
--------------------------

We use the information we collect to provide the SpanishDictionary.com Services to you. Specifically, we use the information to:

* **Provide the SpanishDictionary.com Services you request,** including, for example, processing your requests to sign up for the service, storing your vocabulary lists, and keeping track of your audio preferences on quizzes.
* **Better Understand our Users,** including, for example, conducting research on user preferences, usage patterns, pain points, and interests so that we can improve the Services.
* **Protect the Rights of SpanishDictionary.com and others,** including, for example, using personal information as we believe is necessary or appropriate to protect, enforce, or defend the legal rights, privacy, safety, or property of the Services, its employees or agents, or other users and to comply with applicable law.
* **Deliver Targeted Advertising,** including, for example, using personal information to deliver targeted ads, promotions, and offers to you, on behalf of ourselves and advertisers, on and off the SpanishDictionary.com Services.
* **Recommend Relevant Content,** including, for example, suggesting related words and vocabulary lists that may match your interests.
* **Provide Customer Support,** including, for example, storing your email so that we can respond to messages that we receive and troubleshoot issues that arise on the site.
* **Contact You,** including, for example, to send the Word of the Day email and other information about the SpanishDictionary.com Services, including in connection with your accounts, online surveys, legal notices, new features that you are entitled to access, and other important information. You may opt out of receiving commercial email messages from us by following the instructions contained in those email messages.

For these reasons, we have a legitimate interest in using your information in these ways, as it is fundamental to the nature of the SpanishDictionary.com Services we provide.

How We Share Information
------------------------

As part of providing SpanishDictionary.com Services to you, we may share information with third parties, which can include:

1. **Other Users:** We may share information that you provide use that is meant to be public, such as vocabulary lists and forum posts, with other users of the site.
2. **Advertisers:** We may partner with third party advertisers to provide a customized ad experience on the site that is relevant to your individual interests. In order to identify and deliver personalized advertising, we may share certain information with these partners, including hashed personal information. Likewise, our third party advertising partners may rely on information collected using Cookies on your browser to deliver relevant ad content when you visit the site.
3. **Service Providers:** We may rely on third party providers to support or provide some of the services that are available through the SpanishDictionary.com Services, such as translations. We may also rely on third party providers to perform certain services for us in connection with your use of the SpanishDictionary.com Services, such as communications and hosting services, network security, technical and customer support, tracking and reporting functions, quality assurance testing, payment processing, our own marketing of the SpanishDictionary.com Services, and other functions. We may share information from or about you with these third party providers so that they can perform their services or complete your requests. These third party providers may share information with us that they obtain from or about you in connection with providing their services or completing your requests. Third party providers may also share this information with their subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under common control. Some of our web pages utilize framing techniques to serve content to you from our third party providers, while preserving the look and feel of SpanishDictionary.com Services. In such cases, please note that the information you provide is being provided to the third party.
4. **Business Partners:** We may share information with other third party companies and individuals that we work with to process information on our behalf. For example, we may share data with security consultants to help us better identify spam. Some information we acquire may be collected by third parties on our behalf.
5. **Affiliates:** We may share information from or about you with our parent companies, subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under common control, in which case we will require them to honor this Privacy Policy. If another company acquires Curiosity Media or all or substantially all of our assets, that company will possess the same information, and will assume the rights and obligations with respect to that information as described in this Privacy Policy.
6. **Social Networking Sites:** The SpanishDictionary.com Services may enable you to post content to SNSs (e.g., Facebook or Twitter). If you choose to do this, we will provide information to such SNSs in accordance with your elections. You acknowledge and agree that you are solely responsible for your use of those websites and that it is your responsibility to review the terms of use and privacy policy of the third party provider of such SNSs. We are not responsible or liable for: (i) the availability or accuracy of such SNSs; (ii) the content, products or services made available through such SNSs; or (iii) your use of any such SNSs.
7. **Other Disclosures:** We may investigate and disclose information from or about you if we have a good faith belief that such investigation or disclosure (a) is reasonably necessary to comply with legal process and law enforcement instructions and orders, such as a search warrant, subpoena, statute, judicial proceeding, or other legal process served on us; (b) is helpful to prevent, investigate, or identify possible wrongdoing in connection with SpanishDictionary.com Services; or (c) protects our rights, reputation, property, or that of our users, affiliates, or the public, such as disclosures in connection with our Consumer Alerts program.

Choices You Have About Information
----------------------------------

You may access and update your profile information for your SpanishDictionary.com account [here](https://www.spanishdict.com/users/settings). If you would like to update, correct, modify or delete other personal information you have provided to us, please let us know by contacting us using the information provided in the Contact Us section below. We will comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable.

If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to have your SNS account linked to your SpanishDictionary.com account, you may de-link the SNS account in your SpanishDictionary.com account settings. You may also manage the sharing of certain personal information with us when you connect with us through an SNS. Please refer to the privacy settings of the SNS to determine how you may adjust our permissions and manage the interactivity between the Services and your SNS account or mobile device.

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for record keeping purposes or to complete any transactions that you began prior to requesting such a change or deletion. We will retain your Personal Data for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Policy unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law.

You can stop all collection of information by our Application by uninstalling the Application. You may use the standard uninstall processes as may be available as part of your mobile device or via the mobile application marketplace or network.

You also have choices available to you through the device or software you use to access the SpanishDictionary.com Services. For example:

* The browser you use lets you control Cookies or other types of local data storage
* Your mobile device lets you choose how and whether your location, advertising identifiers and other data is shared with us.

To learn more about these choices, please see the information provided by your device or software provider.

Links to Third Party Sites
--------------------------

SpanishDictionary.com may contain links to unaffiliated third party services. When you click on a link to any other website, you will leave the SpanishDictionary.com Services and go to another site and another entity may collect personal information from you. Except as described in this Privacy Policy, we do not share your personal information with them, and have no control over, do not review, and cannot be responsible for their privacy practices. We suggest you read the privacy policies on or applicable to all such third party services.

Public Information
------------------

You may elect to submit public information to us, including your user name, profile photo, vocabulary lists, forum posts, and other information. By choosing to use these features of SpanishDictionary.com Services, you understand and agree that anyone may access, use, and disclose any information that you submit.

Data Retention and Account Termination
--------------------------------------

You can close your account by clicking [here](https://www.spanishdict.com/users/settings). We may remove your public posts from view or dissociate them from your account profile, but we may also retain information about you for the purposes authorized under this Privacy Policy unless prohibited by law. For example, we may retain information to prevent, investigate, or identify possible wrongdoing in connection with the SpanishDictionary.com Services or to comply with legal obligations.

If you have purchased a subscription of SpanishDictionary.com Premium via our website, you must cancel your Premium subscription prior to closing your account. This enables us to ensure that you are not improperly charged for subscription services after your final subscription period has elapsed. This applies only to web subscriptions of a Premium product, and excludes in-app purchases not directly tied to your SpanishDictionary.com user account.

We will retain your information for at least as long as your account is active, as needed to provide you services or as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

Advertising
-----------

We may use other companies to serve third-party advertisements when you use SpanishDictionary.com Services. These companies may collect and use click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over during your visits to SpanishDictionary.com and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use Log data, Cookie data, and device data to collect this information. Other companies' use of their tracking technologies is subject to their own privacy policies, not this one.

Third parties may be able to associate the information they collect with other information they have about you from other sources. We do not necessarily have access to or control over the Cookies they use, but you may be able to opt out of some of their practices by visiting the following links: [Network Advertising Initiative](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/), [Omniture](https://www.d1.sc.omtrdc.net/optout.html?omniture=1&popup=1&locale=en_US&second=1&second_has_cookie=0), and [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

Please note that opting out does not prevent the display of all advertisements to you. Additionally, we may share non-personally identifiable information from or about you with third parties, such as demographic data, advertising identifiers, or a cryptographic hash of a common account identifier (such as an email address), to facilitate the display of targeted advertising. For example, we may transmit a securely hashed version of your email address to Verizon Media for the purpose of delivering targeted advertisements to you during your time on the site. You can limit our sharing of some of this information through your mobile device settings, as described in the section on managing Cookies above.

We utilize a first-party cookie that facilitates the use of targeted advertising by our third-party advertising partners. To opt yourself out of this cookie, please click [here](#).

To opt-out of the sharing of your personal information, including hashed email address, with advertising partners, please [click here](#).

Children
--------

Children under 13 are not allowed to use SpanishDictionary.com Services. SpanishDictionary.com is intended for general audiences and is not directed to children under 13. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If you become aware that a child has provided us with personal information without parental consent, please contact us [here](https://help.spanishdict.com/). If you are based in the European Economic Area, you may only use SpanishDictionary.com Services if you are over the age at which you can provide consent to data processing under the laws of your country.

Communications
--------------

SpanishDictionary.com offers email and push notifications to provide its services. For example, we offer a daily Word of the Day email or notification. If you no longer want to receive these communications, you may opt-out by click the "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of the email, or turning off the SpanishDictionary.com notification privileges on your mobile operating system.

Security
--------

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. However, no method of transmission over the Internet or via mobile device, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

International Data Transfer
---------------------------

For users residing in the European Economic Area (EEA), please note that the personal data information we obtain from or about you may be transferred, processed and stored outside of the EEA for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy, including in the United States of America. We take the privacy of our users seriously and therefore take steps to safeguard your information to create an adequate level of data protection in accordance with EEA standards. For the purposes of UK and EU data protection legislation, Curiosity Media Inc., a division of IXL Learning, a California corporation with a principle place of business at 777 Mariners Island Blvd., Suite 600, San Mateo, CA 94404, is the "data controller".

Users residing in the EEA also have certain rights related to the collection, storage, use, and retention of your personal information. For example, you may choose to restrict our ability to collect, process, and share your personal data, and you may choose to withdraw consent to the collection, processing, and sharing of your personal data. You may also request access, correction, editing, or erasure of your personal data. If you wish to contact us pursuant to these rights, whether to request access, correction, editing, or deletion of your personal information, to opt out of the use of non-essential data processing, or to withdraw consent previously provided related to your user data, please [contact us](https://help.spanishdict.com/) or [click here](#). To submit a complaint to a data protection authority regarding our use of your personal information, please contact your local data protection authority directly.

Explicit Notice
---------------

Users residing in the states of California, Colorado, Connecticut, Utah, and Virginia are advised that we may collect limited personal information, and share this information with our partners, including our advertising partners, when you use SpanishDictionary.com Services. (For detailed information regarding the specific types of information we collect, the sharing of this information, and your rights regarding this information under US law, please read this Privacy Policy in its entirety.)

As a user in California, Colorado, Connecticut, Utah, or Virginia, you have the additional right to opt out of the sale of your personal information to our third-party advertising partners. Opt-out selections are tracked at the device level; therefore, if you access SpanishDictionary.com Services from multiple devices and wish to exercise your right of opt-out, you must complete the process separately from each relevant device. Please note that opting-out of the sale of your personal data under California, Colorado, Connecticut, Utah, or Virginia law does not mean that you will no longer receive ads when you visit SpanishDictionary.com Services, including some interest-based ads. Furthermore, should you choose to opt out, you may continue to receive targeted advertisements based upon personal information that either predated your opt-out selection by more than 90 days or was collected from external sources from which you have not opted out.

To opt out of the sale of your personal information on this device, please click [here](#). In accordance with California, Colorado, Connecticut, Utah, and Virginia law, we will honor this selection for a period of twelve months or until you clear your cookies on this device, after which point you may renew your opt-out preferences by repeating the normal opt-out process.

Finally, please be advised that we do not disclose your personal information to third parties for the purpose of directly marketing their services to you unless you first agree to such disclosure. However, please be aware that downstream participants may re-sell personal data that has been sold to them with your consent. To opt out of the re-sale of your personal information by a downstream participant, you may use the opt-out links provided [here](https://www.iabprivacy.com/optout.html?mkt_tok=Nzg2LUxCRC01MzMAAAF81uJZcyEjvszcF-G7vB83NuBd9hL3_9Tb37on_CQ0tzrbuxMAAvMqp80DK80DErPSlFbE9WuvYfVv9RC7k0AsU2Qc3amjyN6uS2BhOlFuEIQ). If you have any questions regarding our policies, or would like to change your privacy preferences, you may contact us here or send an email to privacy@spanishdict.com.

Do Not Track Signals
--------------------

Some web browsers may transmit “do-not-track” signals to the websites with which the user communicates. There currently is no consensus among industry participants as to what "Do Not Track" means in this context. Therefore, like many websites and online services, we do not alter their practices when we receive a "Do Not Track" signal from a visitor's browser. To find out more about "Do Not Track," please visit [http://www.allaboutdnt.com](http://www.allaboutdnt.com/).

Sensitive Personal Data
-----------------------

We ask that you not send us, and you not disclose, any sensitive personal data, which may include, for example, social security numbers, information related to racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religion or other beliefs, health, biometrics or genetic characteristics, criminal background or trade union membership. If you send or disclose any sensitive personal data to us, you consent to our processing and use of such sensitive personal data in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If you do not consent to our processing and use of such sensitive personal data, you must not send us such content.

Modifications to This Privacy Policy
------------------------------------

We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. The most current version of the Privacy Policy will govern our collection, use, and disclosure of information about you. We will notify you of changes by posting changes [here](https://www.spanishdict.com/company/privacy), or by other appropriate means. Any changes to the Privacy Policy will become effective when the updated policy is posted [here](https://www.spanishdict.com/company/privacy). Your use of SpanishDictionary.com Services or your provision of personal information to use the SpanishDictionary.com Services following such changes indicates your acceptance of the revised Privacy Policy.

Contact Us
----------

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, please feel free to contact us [here](https://help.spanishdict.com/).

SpanishDictionary.com is the world's most popular Spanish-English dictionary, translation, and learning website.

Copyright © 2024 Curiosity Media, Inc., a division of IXL Learning

SpanishDictionary.com is the world's most popular Spanish-English dictionary, translation, and learning website.

FEATURES

ABOUT

SOCIAL NETWORKS

APPS

Making educational experiences better for everyone.

[

English dictionary and learning for Spanish speakers](https://www.xn--ingls-esa.com/)[

French-English dictionary, translator, and learning](https://www.frenchdictionary.com/)[

Immersive learning for 25 languages](https://www.rosettastone.com/)[

Comprehensive resource for word definitions and usage](https://www.dictionary.com/)[

Essential reference for synonyms and antonyms](https://www.thesaurus.com/)[

Adaptive learning for English vocabulary](https://www.vocabulary.com/)[

Fast, easy, reliable language certification](https://www.emmersion.ai/)[

Fun educational games for kids](https://www.abcya.com/)[

Trusted tutors for 300+ subjects](https://www.wyzant.com/)[

Comprehensive K-12 personalized learning](https://www.ixl.com/)[

Marketplace for millions of educator-created resources](https://www.teacherspayteachers.com/)[

35,000+ worksheets, games, and lesson plans](https://www.education.com/)

Copyright © 2024 Curiosity Media, Inc., a division of IXL Learning • All Rights Reserved.
